In 1962 at Rice University,
في عام 1962 في جامعة رايس،
JFK told the country about a dream he had,
أخبر الرئيس (جون كينيدي) البلد عن حلمه،
a dream to put a person on the moon by the end of the decade.
حَلُمَ أن يوصل شخصاً إلى القمر مع نهاية العقد.
The eponymous moonshot.
وسمّيَ ذلكَ لاحقاً برمية القمر.
No one knew if it was possible to do
لم يعرف أحد ما إذا كان من الممكن فعل ذلك
but he made sure a plan was put in place to do it if it was possible.
ولكنه تأكد من أنّ الخطة وُضعت موضع التنفيذ لفعل ذلك إن كان بالإمكان.
That's how great dreams are.
هكذا هي الأحلام العظيمة.
Great dreams aren't just visions,
ليست الأحلام العظيمة مجرّد رؤى،
they're visions coupled to strategies for making them real.
إنها رؤى مصحوبة بإستراتيجيات لجعلها حقيقة.
I have the incredible good fortune to work at a moonshot factory.
أنا محظوظ لدرجة لا تصدق كوني أعمل في مصنع للمشاريع الخلاقّة.
At X -- formerly called Google X --
في إكس -- سابقاً غوغل إكس--
you'll find an aerospace engineer working alongside a fashion designer
ستجدون مهندس فضاء يعمل جنباً الى جنب مع مصمم ملابس
and former military ops commanders brainstorming with laser experts.
وقادة عمليات عسكرية سابقون يتبادلون الأفكار مع مختصين في الليزر.
These inventors, engineers and makers are dreaming up technologies
يحلم هؤلاء المخترعون والمهندسون والمصنّعون بتقنيات
that we hope can make the world a wonderful place.
نأمل أنّ باستطاعتها جعل العالم مكاناً رائعاً.
We use the word "moonshots" to remind us to keep our visions big --
نستخدم عبارة "رمية القمر" لكي تذكرّنا بإبقاء رؤانا عظيمة --
to keep dreaming.
لنظل نحلم.
And we use the word "factory" to remind ourselves
ونستخدم كلمة "مصنع" لتذكير أنفسنا
that we want to have concrete visions --
بأننا نريد امتلاك رؤى ثابتة --
concrete plans to make them real.
خطط ثابتة لجعلها حقيقة.
Here's our moonshot blueprint.
هذا هو مخططنا لمشروع رمية القمر.
Number one:
رقم واحد:
we want to find a huge problem in the world
نريد إيجاد مشكلة عويصة في العالم
that affects many millions of people.
تؤثر على ملايين كثيرة من البشر.
Number two:
رقم اثنين:
we want to find or propose a radical solution for solving that problem.
نريد إيجاد أو اقتراح حل جذري لحل تلك المشكلة.
And then number three:
ومن ثمّ رقم ثلاثة:
there has to be some reason to believe
يجب أن يكون هنالك سبب للإيمان
that the technology for such a radical solution
بأنّ التقنية لذلك الحل الجذري
could actually be built.
يمكن بناءها على أرض الواقع.
But I have a secret for you.
ولكن عندي سر لكم.
The moonshot factory is a messy place.
وهو أنّ مصنع رمية القمر مكان فوضوي.
But rather than avoid the mess,
ولكن بدلاً عن تجنب الفوضى،
pretend it's not there,
ندّعي عدم وجودها،
we've tried to make that our strength.
لقد حاولنا جعل ذلك نقطة قوتنا.
We spend most of our time breaking things
نقضي معظم وقتنا في تعطيل الأشياء
and trying to prove that we're wrong.
وفي محاولة إثبات أننا مخطؤون.
That's it, that's the secret.
ذلك هو، ذلك هو السر.
Run at all the hardest parts of the problem first.
اصطدم بأصعب أجزاء المشكلة بدايةً.
Get excited and cheer,
اشعر بالإثارة وابتهج،
"Hey! How are we going to kill our project today?"
"أنت! كيف سنقوم سنعطّل مشروعنا اليوم؟"
We've got this interesting balance going
لدينا هذه الموازنة الشيّقة
where we allow our unchecked optimism to fuel our visions.
حيث نسمح لتفاؤلنا غير المنضبط بإشعال جذوة رؤانا.
But then we also harness enthusiastic skepticism
ولكن من ثم نسخِّر أيضاً شكّنا الحماسي
to breathe life, breathe reality into those visions.
لنفخ الحياة ولنفخ الواقع في تلك الرؤى.
I want to show you a few of the projects
أودّ أن أعرض عليكم بعض المشاريع
that we've had to leave behind on the cutting room floor,
التي توجب علينا نسيانها على أرضية غرفة المونتاج،
and also a few of the gems
وقليل من الجواهر أيضاً
that at least so far, have not only survived that process,
التي، حتى الآن على الأقل، لم تنجُ فقط من تلك العملية،
but have been accelerated by it.
وإنما قد تسارعت بها.
Last year we killed a project in automated vertical farming.
ألغينا العام الماضي مشروعاً في الزراعة العمودية الآلية.
This is some of the lettuce that we grew.
هذا بعض من الخس الذي زرعناه.
One in nine people in the world suffers from undernourishment.
يعاني واحد من بين كل تسعة أشخاص حول العالم من نقص التغذية.
So this is a moonshot that needs to happen.
لذلك هذا هدف واجب التحقيق.
Vertical farming uses 10 times less water
تستخدم الزراعة العمودية مياهً أقل بعشر مرات
and a hundred times less land than conventional farming.
ومساحات أقل بمئة مرة من الزراعة التقليدية.
And because you can grow the food close to where it's consumed,
ولأن باستطاعتك زراعة الغذاء قريباً من مكان الاستهلاك،
you don't have to transport it large distances.
إذاً لا نحتاج نقلها لمسافات بعيدة.
We made progress in a lot of the areas
أحرزنا تقدماً في الكثير من المجالات
like automated harvesting and efficient lighting.
كالحصاد الآلي والإضاءة الفعَّالة.
But unfortunately,
ولكن للأسف،
we couldn't get staple crops like grains and rice to grow this way.
لم نتمكن من زراعة المحاصيل الرئيسية كالحبوب والأرُز بهذه الطريقة.
So we killed the project.
لذلك ألغينا المشروع.
Here's another huge problem.
هنا مشكلة عويصة أخرى.
We pay enormous costs in resources and environmental damage
ندفع تكلفة باهظة في الموارد والضرر البيئي
to ship goods worldwide.
لشحن البضائع حول العالم.
Economic development of landlocked countries
النمو الاقتصادي في البلدان المحاطة باليابسة
is limited by lack of shipping infrastructure.
محدود بسبب نقص بنى النقل التحتية.
The radical solution?
ما هو الحل الجذري؟
A lighter-than-air, variable-buoyancy cargo ship.
سفينة شحن أخف من الهواء، ومتغيرة الطفوية.
This has the potential to lower,
لهذا القدرة على تقليل،
at least overall,
على الأقل بصورة عامة،
the cost, time and carbon footprint of shipping
التكلفة والوقت وانبعاث الكربون الناتج عن النقل
without needing runways.
دون الحاجة الى طرق.
We came up with this clever set of technical breakthroughs
توصلّنا الى هذه المجموعة من الاكتشافات التقنية الذكية
that together might make it possible for us to lower the cost enough
التي ربما تسهل علينا سويةً تقليل الكلفة بصورة كافية
that we could actually make these ships --
بحيث نستطيع صناعة هذه السفن --
inexpensively enough in volume.
بسعر مناسب كفاية لنصنعها بالجملة.
But however cheap they would have been to make in volume
ولكن مهما كان صناعتها بالجملة رخيصاً
it turned out that it was going to cost close to 200 million dollars
تبيّن أنّ ذلك كان ليكلف قرابة 200 مليون دولار
to design and build the first one.
لتصميم وبناء السفينة الأولى.
200 million dollars is just way too expensive.
إنّ 200 مليون دولار كلفة كبيرة جداً.
Because X is structured with these tight feedback loops
لأنّ (إكس) مبني على هذه الحلقات الإرتجاعية الضيقة
of making mistakes and learning and new designs,
من عمل الأخطاء والتعلم منها والتصاميم الجديدة،
we can't spend 200 million dollars
ولا يمكننا إنفاق 200 مليون دولار
to get the first data point
للحصول على أول نقطة بيانات
about whether we're on the right track or not.
لمعرفة ما إذا كنا في المسار الصحيح أم لا.
If there's an Achilles' heel in one our projects,
إن كان هنالك نقطة ضعف في مشاريعنا،
we want to know it now, up front, not way down the road.
فإننا نريد معرفتها الآن، في التو واللحظة، وليس خلال مراحل العمل.
So we killed this project, too.
لذا فقد ألغينا هذا المشروع أيضاً.
Discovering a major flaw in a project
إنّ اكتشاف هفوة كبرى في المشروع
doesn't always mean that it ends the project.
لا يعني دائماً نهاية المشروع.
Sometimes it actually gets us onto a more productive path.
في بعض الأحيان يقودنا ذلك الى سبيل أكثر إنتاجية.
This is our fully self-driving vehicle prototype,
هذا نموذج لمركبة قيادة ذاتية تامّة من صنعنا،
which we built without a steering wheel or break pedal.
والتي بنيناها دون عجلة تحكم أو دواسة فرامل.
But that wasn't actually our goal when we started.
ولكن في الحقيقة لم يكن ذلك هدفنا عندما بدأنا.
With 1.2 million people dying on the roads globally every year,
بنسبة تصل إلى 1.2 مليون شخص يموتون نتيجة حوادث السير عالمياً كل عام،
building a car that drives itself was a natural moonshot to take.
كان بناءُ سيارة ذاتية القيادة رمية نحو القمر يجب اطلاقها.
Three and a half years ago,
قبل ثلاثة سنوات ونصف،
when we had these Lexus, retrofitted, self-driving cars in testing,
عندما كنا نختبر سيارات الليكزيس المعدّلة ذاتية القيادة،
they were doing so well, we gave them out to other Googlers
كانت تبلي بلاءً حسناً، فأعطيناهم لموظفي غوغل آخرين
to find out what they thought of the experience.
لمعرفة انطباعاتهم عن تلك التجربة.
And what we discovered
وكان ما اكتشفناه
was that our plan to have the cars do almost all the driving
هو أنّ خطتنا في جعل السيارات تقوم بعملية القيادة كلها تقريباً
and just hand over to the users in case of emergency
وإتاحة القيادة للمستخدم في حالات الطوارئ فقط
was a really bad plan.
كانت في الحقيقة خطة سيئة.
It wasn't safe
لم تكن آمنة
because the users didn't do their job.
لأنّ المستخدمين لم يقوموا بعملهم.
They didn't stay alert
لم يبقوا متيقظين
in case the car needed to hand control back to them.
في حال احتاجت السيارة تحويل عملية القيادة إليهم.
This was a major crisis for the team.
كانت هذه أزمة كبرى للفريق.
It sent them back to the drawing board.
أعادتهم مرة ثانية الى لوح التصميم.
And they came up with a beautiful, new perspective.
وخرجوا بفكرة جميلة بمنظور جديد.
Aim for a car where you're truly a passenger.
تهدف الى سيارة بحيث تكون أنت فيها راكباً بحق.
You tell the car where you want to go,
تُخبر السيارة بوجهتك،
you push a button
تضغطُ على زر
and it takes you from point A to point B by itself.
وتأخذك السيارة من النقطة آ الى النقطة ب بمفردها.
We're really grateful
كنا ممتنين جداً
that we had this insight as early on in the project as we did.
لخروجنا بهذه الفكرة في بداية المشروع كما حدث.
And it's shaped everything we've done since then.
وقد شكلّت كل شيء فعلناه منذ ذلك الحين.
And now our cars have self-driven more than 1.4 million miles,
والآن قادت سياراتنا نفسها ذاتياً لأكثر من 1.4 مليون ميل،
and they're out everyday
وهي تسير في الخارج يومياً
on the streets of Mountain View, California and Austin, Texas.
في شوارع (ماونتن فيو) في كاليفورنيا، و (أوستن) في تِكساس.
The cars team shifted their perspective.
ارتقى فريق السيارات بمنظورهم.
This is one of X's mantras.
وهذه إحدى أنشودات (إكس).
Sometimes shifting your perspective is more powerful than being smart.
في بعض الأحيان تغيير منظورك أكثر فعالية من أن تكون ذكياً.
Take wind energy.
خذوا طاقة الرياح مثلاً.
It's one of my favorite examples of perspective shifting.
إنه أحد أمثلتي المفضلّة عن تغيير المنظور.
There's no way that we're going to build
ليس هنالك من طريقة يمكننا بها بناء
a better standard wind turbine than the experts in that industry.
توربين هواء معياري أفضل من الخبراء في تلك الصناعة.
But we found a way to get up higher into the sky,
ولكننا اكتشفنا طريقة للإرتفاع أعلى نحو السماء،
and so get access to faster, more consistent winds,
وبذلك الحصول على رياح أسرع وأكثر استمرارية،
and so more energy without needing hundreds of tons of steel to get there.
ومن ثمّ المزيد من الطاقة دون الحاجة الى مئات الأطنان من الفولاذ للوصول الى هناك.
Our Makani energy kite rises up from its perch
فإنّ طائرة الطاقة (ماكاني) ترتفع من موقعها نحو الأعلى
by spinning up those propellers along its wing.
بواسطة تدوير تلك المراوح المثبتة على أجنحتها.
And it pulls out a tether as it rises,
وتسحب معها سلكاً مثبِّتاً وهي ترتفع،
pulling energy up through the tether.
ساحبة الطاقة عن طريق السلك.
Once the tether's all the way out,
وعندما يصبح السلك كله في الأعلى،
it goes into crosswind circles in the sky.
تدور في دورات مضادة للريح في السماء.
And now those propellers that lifted it up have become flying turbines.
والآن أصبحت تلك المراوح التي رفعتها توربينات طائرة.
And that sends energy back down the tether.
وذلك يعيد الطاقة الى الأسفل من خلال السلك.
We haven't yet found a way to kill this project.
لم نجد حتى الآن طريقة لإلغاء المشروع.
And the longer it survives that pressure, the more excited we get
وكلما نجت من ذلك الضغط، كلما زادت إثارتنا
that this could become a cheaper and more deployable form
بأنّ هذا قد يكون شكلاً أرخص وأكثر قابلية للنشر
of wind energy for the world.
للإستفادة من طاقة الرياح للعالم.
Probably the craziest sounding project we have is Project Loon.
ربما يبدو (مشروع لون) أكثر مشاريعنا جنوناً.
We're trying to make balloon-powered Internet.
نحاول توفير شبكة إنترنت مطلقة من منطاد.
A network of balloons in the stratosphere
شبكة من المناطيد في طبقة الغلاف الجوي العليا
that beam an internet connection down to rural and remote areas of the world.
والتي تبث اتصال الإنترنت الى الأسفل الى المناطق الريفية والنائية من العالم.
This could bring online as many as four billion more people,
وبوسع ذلك توفير الاتصال لحوالي أربع مليارات انسان،
who today have little or no internet connection.
والذين ليس لديهم حالياً اتصال أو اتصال رديء.
But you can't just take a cell tower,
ولكن لا يمكنك ببساطة أخذ برج خلوي،
strap it to a balloon and stick it in the sky.
وربطه بمنطاد، وتثبيته في السماء.
The winds are too strong, it would be blown away.
فالرياح قوية جداً، وستأخذه بعيداً.
And the balloons are too high up to tie it to the ground.
والمناطيد أعلى بكثير من أن تُربط بالأرض.
Here comes the crazy moment.
وهنا تأتي اللحظة المجنونة.
What if, instead,
ماذا لو، بدل ذلك،
we let the balloons drift
نترك المناطيد تنجرف
and we taught them how to sail the winds to go where the needed to go?
ونعلمّها كيف تبحر في الريح لتذهب حيث يجب عليها الذهاب؟
It turns out the stratosphere has winds
ولكن تبيّن أن رياح طبقة الغلاف الجوي العليا
that are going in quite different speeds and directions in thin strata.
تسير بسرعات واتجاهات مختلفة تماماً عن تلك التي في الطبقات الخفيفة.
So we hoped that using smart algorithms and wind data from around the world,
لذا أمِلنا أننا باستخدام خوارزميات ذكية وبيانات الرياح من حول العالم،
we could maneuver the balloons a bit,
سنتمكن من جعل البالونات تناوِر قليلاً،
getting them to go up and down just a tiny bit in the stratosphere
جاعلينها تصعد وتهبط قليلاً في طبقة الغلاف الجوي العيا
to grab those winds going in those different directions and speeds.
لالتقاط تلك الرياح الذاهبة في تلك الاتجاهات والسرعات المختلفة.
The idea is to have enough balloons
الفكرة هي امتلاك عدد كاف من المناطيد
so as one balloon floats out of your area,
بحيث عندما يطفو المنطاد بعيداً عن منطقتك،
there's another balloon ready to float into place,
يكون هنالك منطاد آخر جاهز ليطفو مكانه،
handing off the internet connection,
مسلّماً اتصال الإنترنت،
just like your phone hands off between cell towers
كما يستلم هاتفك الاشارة من برج وينتقل الى آخر
as you drive down the freeway.
عندما تقود على الطريق السريع.
We get how crazy that vision sounds --
نفهم كم تبدو تلك الرؤية مجنونة --
there's the name of the project to remind us of that.
فاسم المشروع يذكرنا بذلك دائماً.
So since 2012,
لذا فمنذ العام 2012،
the Loon team has prioritized the work that seems the most difficult
جعل فريق (لون) العمل الأصعب أولوية
and so the most likely to kill their project.
والذي من الأرجح أن يلغي المشروع.
The first thing that they did
كان أول ما فعلوه
was try to get a Wi-Fi connection from a balloon in the stratosphere
هو الحصول على اتصال واي-فاي من منطاد في طبقة الجو العليا
down to an antenna on the ground.
الى هوائي على الأرض.
It worked.
نجح ذلك.
And I promise you there were bets that it wasn't going to.
وأعدكم بأنه كان هنالك فقرات لم تكن لتنجح.
So we kept going.
لذا فقد واصلنا العمل.
Could we get the balloon to talk directly to handsets,
هل يمكننا جعل المنطاد التواصل مباشرة مع الهاتف،
so that we didn't need the antenna as an intermediary receiver?
فلا نحتاج الى الهوائي كمستقبلٍ وسيط؟
Yeah.
نعم.
Could we get the balloon bandwidth high enough
هل بإمكاننا جعل مدى تردد المنطاد عالياً كفاية
so it was a real Internet connection?
ليكون اتصال إنترنت حقيقي؟
So that people could have something more than just SMS?
حتى يحصل الناس على شيء أكثر من رسائل نصية فقط؟
The early tests weren't even a megabit per second,
لم تصل الاختبارات المبكرة الى سرعة ميغابت لكل ثانية حتى،
but now we can do up to 15 megabits per second.
ولكن الآن يمكننا الوصول الى سرعة 15 ميغابت لكل ثانية.
Enough to watch a TED Talk.
سرعة تكفي لمشاهدة محادثة TED.
Could we get the balloons to talk to each other through the sky
هل بإمكاننا جعل المناطيد تتحاور مع بعضها في السماء
so that we could reach our signal deeper into rural areas?
فنستطيع إيصال إشارتنا الى عمق المناطق الريفية؟
Check.
تَم.
Could we get balloons the size of a house to stay up for more than 100 days,
هل بإمكاننا جعل مناطيد بحجم منزل البقاء محلّقة لأكثر من 100 يوم،
while costing less than five percent
وبكلفة أقل من 5%
of what traditional, long-life balloons have cost to make?
من كلفة المناطيد التقليدية طويلة الأمد؟
Yes. In the end.
نعم. في نهاية الأمر.
But I promise you, you name it, we had to try it to get there.
ولكن أعدكم، مهما كان الأمر، كان علينا التجربة للوصول.
We made round, silvery balloons.
صنعنا مناطيد دائرية فضية.
We made giant pillow-shaped balloons.
صنعنا مناطيد عملاقة على شكل وسائد.
We made balloons the size of a blue whale.
صنعنا مناطيد بحجم الحوت الأزرق.
We busted a lot of balloons.
فجرّنا الكثير من المناطيد.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Since one of the things that was most likely to kill the Loon project
وبما أنّ أحد الأشياء التي كان من المحتمل أن تُلغي مشروع (لون)
was whether we could guide the balloons through the sky,
هو قدرتنا على توجيه المناطيد في السماء،
one of our most important experiments was putting a balloon inside a balloon.
كانت إحدى أهم تجاربنا وضع منطاد داخل منطاد.
So there are two compartments here, one with air and then one with helium.
فيكون لدينا جزئين، واحد مملوء بالهواء، والآخر بالهليوم.
The balloon pumps air in to make itself heavier,
يضخ المنطاد الهواء لجعل نفسه أثقل،
or lets air out to make it lighter.
أو يتخلص من الهواء لجعله أخف.
And these weight changes allow it to rise or fall,
وتسمح هذه التغيرات في الوزن للمنطاد بالصعود والهبوط،
and that simple movement of the balloon is its steering mechanism.
وتلك الحركة البسيطة للمنطاد هي آلية توجيهه.
It floats up or down,
يطفو صعوداً وهبوطاً،
hoping to grab winds going in the speed and direction that it wants.
أملاً في لقاء ريح تنتقل بالسرعة والاتجاه المرغوب بهما.
But is that good enough for it to navigate through the world?
ولكن هل ذلك يكفي المنطاد للملاحة عبر العالم؟
Barely at first,
بالكاد في البداية،
but better all the time.
ولكن يتم تحسينه دائماً.
This particular balloon, our latest balloon,
هذا المنطاد بالذات، آخر مناطيدنا،
can navigate a two-mile vertical stretch of sky
يمكنه الملاحة ميلين عموديين في السماء
and can sail itself to within 500 meters of where it wants to go
ويمكنه الإبحار بنفسه الى مسافة 500 متر إلى حيث يريد الذهاب
from 20,000 kilometers away.
من على بعد 20 ألف كيلومتر.
We have lots more to do
أمامنا الكثير لفعله
in terms of fine-tuning the system and reducing costs.
من حيث المعايرة الدقيقة للنظام وتقليل الكلفة.
But last year, a balloon built inexpensively
ولكن العام الماضي، بُني منطاد بكلفة قليلة
went around the world 19 times over 187 days.
دار حول العالم 19 مرة خلال 187 يوماً.
So we're going to keep going.
لذا فإننا مستمرون.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Our balloons today
إنّ مناطيدنا اليوم
are doing pretty much everything a complete system needs to do.
تفعل تقريبا كلّ ما يجب على المنظومة الكاملة فعله.
We're in discussions with telcos around the world,
نخوض مباحثات مع شركات الإتصالات حول العالم،
and we're going to fly over places like Indonesia
وسنحلّق في أماكن مثل إندونيسيا
for real service testing this year.
لاختبار خدمة حقيقي هذا العام.
This probably all sounds too good to be true,
يبدو ذلك، على الأرجح، أحسن من أن يكون حقيقة،
and you're right.
وأنتم محقون.
Being audacious
فكونك جسوراً
and working on big, risky things
والعمل على أشياء كبيرة ومليئة بالمخاطرة
makes people inherently uncomfortable.
تجعل الناس غير مرتاحين بصورة كبيرة.
You cannot yell at people and force them to fail fast.
لا يمكنك الصياح على الناس وإجبارهم على الفشل سريعاً.
People resist. They worry.
الناس يقاومون ويقلقون.
"What will happen to me if I fail?
"ماذا سيحدث لي لو فشلت؟
Will people laugh at me?
هل سيضحك الناس علي؟
Will I be fired?"
هل سأُطرَد؟"
I started with our secret.
بدأتُ بالحديث عن سرّنا.
I'm going to leave you with how we actually make it happen.
وسأختم بكيف جعلنا الأمر ينجح.
The only way to get people to work on big, risky things --
إنّ الطريقة الوحيدة لجعل الناس يعملون على أشياء كبيرة وفيها مخاطرة--
audacious ideas --
أفكار جريئة --
and have them run at all the hardest parts of the problem first,
وجعلهم يواجهون جميع الأجزاء الصعبة من المشكلة في البداية،
is if you make that the path of least resistance for them.
هي جعل تلك الطريق الأقل مقاومة بالنسبة لهم.
We work hard at X to make it safe to fail.
إننا نعمل بجدّ في (إكس) لجعل من الآمن أن تفشل.
Teams kill their ideas as soon as the evidence is on the table
تنهي الفرق أفكارها حالما تتوفر الأدلة لذلك
because they're rewarded for it.
لأنهم يكرّمون لذلك.
They get applause from their peers.
يلاقون التصفيق من أقرانهم.
Hugs and high fives from their manager, me in particular.
أحضان وتحايا من مدرائهم، منّي خصوصاً.
They get promoted for it.
ويحصلون على ترقيات لأجل ذلك.
We have bonused every single person on teams that ended their projects,
لقد كافئنا كل فرد من الفرق التي ألغت مشاريعها
from teams as small as two to teams of more than 30.
من فرق تتألف من شخصين وحتى الفرق التي فاقت 30 شخصاً.
We believe in dreams at the moonshot factory.
إننا نؤمن بالأحلام في مصنع رمية القمر.
But enthusiastic skepticism
ولكن الشك الحماسي
is not the enemy of boundless optimism.
ليس عدواً للتفاؤل اللامحدود.
It's optimism's perfect partner.
إنه رفيق التفاؤل المثالي.
It unlocks the potential in every idea.
إنّه يحرر الإمكانيات في كل فكرة.
We can create the future that's in our dreams.
باستطاعتنا خلق المستقبل الموجود في أحلامنا.
Thank you very much.
شكراً جزيلاً لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)